hiredesk.net 2019-10-23

# Privacy Policy | Talemetry

## Talemetry Inc. General Website Privacy Notice

**Updated 2018.05.03**

Talemetry Inc. (“WE”, “US”, OR “TALEMETRY”) understands that you care about how information about you is used. This privacy notice explains how we collect personal information pertaining to you (“Information”) through our website (the “Site”); how we maintain, use and share that Information; and how you can manage the way Information about you is handled.

## Protection of Personal Information Laws

Talemetry is based in Canada and therefore Canadian law generally governs our collection, use, and disclosure of personal information in a manner that recognizes individuals’ right of privacy with respect to their personal information. If you are resident in the European Union the European General Data Regulation (“GDPR”) coming into effect on May 25, 2018 may apply to Talemetry’s collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information.

Talemetry does not collect, use or disclose your personal information without your consent except where required or allowed by law.

_Talemetry processes, stores, and accesses Information in Canada, the United States, and other jurisdictions._

**In using this Site and in providing Information to Talemetry, you consent to your Information being transferred outside your home country to Canada or other jurisdictions where Talemetry processes, stores, and accesses the Information as described in this privacy notice.**

## How does Talemetry Collect and Use Information?

In order to use certain Talemetry products and services, you may be required to register as a user. If you register as a user from time to time we may use your email address to send you information and keep you informed of our products and services.

**Registering as a user represents your consent to receive our emails as described above.**

You will always be provided with an opportunity to opt out of receiving such information and  _you can withdraw your consent to receive our emails at any time_. Your contact Information may also be used to reach you regarding issues concerning your use of our Site, including changes to this privacy notice.

Talemetry may aggregate Information in a form that does not allow users to be personally identified to provide and enhance services that we provide our customers. Talemetry may conduct its business through a number of different legal entities. Therefore, your Information may be shared between Talemetry and its affiliates. However, in all cases, the Talemetry affiliate shall comply with this privacy notice as if you originally provided the Information directly to it. Talemetry and its affiliates will to the extent practical, co-ordinate the updating, storage, and processing of your Information so as minimize the creation of inconsistent versions of the Information.

## Job Applicants

Your provision of Information to Talemetry in connection to recruiting is voluntary, and you determine the information you provide to us; however please note that if you decide not to provide information, it may affect our ability to consider you for employment. Applying for a job with us includes registering as a job applicant with us.

The information you provide in relation to recruiting will be used to communicate with you, to manage Talemetry’s recruiting and hiring processes, and for compliance with corporate governance and legal and regulatory requirements. If you are hired, the information will be used in connection with employment and corporate management and will be subject to Talemetry’s internal privacy policies.

**If you apply for a job with us you are consenting to receive emails from us regarding your application or other jobs with us which may interest you.**

_Talemetry may retain your Information for up to 3 years from the date of your application for a job to consider you for other job opportunities._  We may also email you to make you aware of other job opportunities at Talemetry. To the extent permitted or required by law, Talemetry may delete your Information at any time.

**You may contact us at any time and request the modification, update, deletion, or return of your Information which we hold or to request that we no longer email you regarding jobs that may interest you.**

### General Site Interactions, Information Requests, and Sales Inquiries

When you interact with the Site we collect Information from offline and online registrations and forms, communications and interactions, and sales inquiries and transactions. We may also obtain information from third party sources, such as opt-in lists and combine that information with Information you provide.

In general, the Information collected from you is contact information, such as name, address, telephone number, email address, and company. We also collect user preferences including opt-in and opt-out preferences for marketing and other communications from Talemetry and information related to your use of the Site (see the “Cookies” section).

Talemetry uses the Information to: engage in commercial transactions, to provide support or other services related to our products, to tailor marketing to your needs and respond to your requests, to provide online forums, to communicate with you about a conference or an event, and to select content, improve quality and facilitate the use of the Site.

**We will store Information related to non-job applicants for up to 4 years from the last active interaction we have with you**  (for example a request from you, an email from you, the opening of our email to you, your visiting the Site, etc.). We may delete your Information at an earlier date in our sole discretion.  _You may, in accordance with this privacy notice, ask us to delete, modify, or provide you a copy of your Information we store_.

**In using this Site and in providing Information to Talemetry, you consent to the use of your Information as described in this privacy notice, including the receipt of communications from Talemetry and the sharing of your Information with Talemetry affiliates.**

Talemetry uses third parties, including hosting managed service providers and application providers providing email processing, contact management, and document storage, in Canada and the United States, and your Information will be processed, stored, and accessed by such third parties.  _For Information subject to the GDPR, Talemetry relies on adequacy decisions related to the country of transfer, Privacy Shield certifications of the third parties, and specific data processing agreements with third parties containing approved standard data protection clauses as appropriate as the legal basis for the transfer to the third country._

**In using this Site and in providing Information to Talemetry, you consent to such hosting and processing of your Information by these third parties including the transfer of your information to Canada and the United States.**

We also collect information using cookies, as described below.

### Cookies

Most websites, including our Site, use a feature of your browser to set a small text file called a “cookie” on your computer. The Site can then recognize the computer when you revisit the Site to allow auto log in and track how you are using the Site. Cookies may also allow us to make advertising offers to you on other internet websites through various internet advertising networks.

When you visit our Site, our servers and/or those of our service providers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends, such as your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, referring/exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, time and date of use and other information (“Anonymous Information”). Some cookies may remain on your computer after you leave the Site.

The information we collect using cookies does not allow you to be personally identified; but we may link this information to Information that you submit while on our Site, which does allow you to be personally identified.  _You are free to decline cookies. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, erase cookies or notify you when a cookie is set. (see  _[www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies) _)_  You should be aware however that rejecting or erasing cookies from the Site may result in certain aspects of the Site not operating when you visit it.

_On the Site, we may also use embedded pixel technologies on selected pages_  for the purposes of identifying unique user visits to the Site as opposed to aggregate hits. In addition, embedded pixels or other technologies may be used in emails to provide information on when the email was opened to track marketing campaign responsiveness. Information collected using these technologies may be associated with your Information.  **In using the Site, you are consenting to Talemetry placing cookies and other related technologies on your computer to the extent that you have configured your browser to accept them.**

## When does Talemetry Share Information?

##### Disclosures to Service Providers

Talemetry discloses Information to service providers, solely for providing functions related to our operation of the Site or for processing your Information for the purposes we have collected it as described above, and for no other purpose. For example: Talemetry may use software hosted by a service provider to provide us with information regarding our visitors’ activities on our Site. When you visit our Site, that service provider may set cookies on our behalf and may receive information about your browsing activity on our Site.

##### Disclosures for Legal Reasons

We may disclose Information to a third party if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary or desirable: (i) to comply with a law, regulation, governmental or securities exchange requirement, court order, judicial proceeding or legal process, such as a subpoena or a search warrant, (ii) to address a violation of the law, (iii) to protect the rights, property or safety of Talemetry, its users or the public, or (iv) to allow Talemetry to exercise its legal rights or respond to a legal claim.

##### Disclosures to a Buyer of the Company

If our company or substantially all of our assets are acquired, or in the event of a merger or bankruptcy, your Information may be among the transferred assets.  **In using the Site you are consenting to Talemetry sharing your Information as described in this privacy notice.**

## How Can You Opt Out of Certain Uses of Your Information?

Talemetry gives you the opportunity to “opt out” of having your Information used for certain purposes. If you no longer wish to receive our communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication to unsubscribe. After we receive your request, we will send you an email message to confirm that you have been unsubscribed.

Talemetry will not share Information with third parties for promotional uses unless you opt in to such sharing within your Talemetry account or Talemetry has separately acquired such Information from other sources, in which case Talemetry will give you the opportunity to opt-out via email.  **You may withdraw your consent to the continued collection, use or disclosure of your personal information by Talemetry at any time**  by sending an email to privacy@talemetry.com or by calling +1-866-447-3933, +44-20-3287-2395, or +1-604-278-4414), but such a request would be subject to legal or contractual restrictions. We would also require reasonable advance notice to effect any requested changes. A request that we no longer collect or use your Registration Information or certain User Information or Anonymous Information, may mean that we will no longer have practical means to provide you with our services or products. You may no longer be able to log in to our Site or may lose certain functionality when visiting the Site, including functionality that depends on such information.

## Information from Children

We do not collect Information from kids. We do not collect any type of information from a person known to be under the age of 13. If we discover that we have accidentally collected information from a child, we will remove the information from our records as soon as feasibly possible (or obtain the necessary parental permission to retain it).

## Improper Use of Information

Although we use reasonable means to ensure that third parties do not use the Information you provide to us for purposes other than those described in this privacy notice, Talemetry is not responsible for any improper use of your personal information that is beyond our reasonable control.

## Access and Accuracy and Update of Personal Information

We will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal Information is as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is appropriate for its purposes.

Talemetry provides you in some cases, such as our career portal, with the means to access, update, edit or delete your Information you have provided to us on your own by going to the Site, logging on, and changing or deleting your Information and other data.

You may similarly contact us to address errors or omissions relating to your personal information by emailing [privacy@talemetry.com](mailto:privacy@talemetry.com) or by telephoning +1-866-447-3933, +44-20-3287-2395, or +1-604-278-4414.  _Be aware that we will take steps to verify it is you who is requesting any changes before we make them._

Upon request made in writing, Talemetry will inform you of the existence, use and disclosure of your Information, at minimal or no cost to you, in accordance with processes and procedures that we have put in place for such requests. If you are unsure whether we have a record containing your Information and would like to confirm what Information we have, please send an email to privacy@talemetry.com with your request, identifying all email addresses which you may have given us. If there is a cost involved at all, we will inform you at that time.

_We may require additional information from you in order to verify your identity following an access request. Such personal information will only be used for the purpose of identity verification and will itself be subject to protection under the terms of this Privacy Notice._  Talemetry will respond to all requests for access within 30 days or as otherwise required or permitted by law.

In some circumstances, we may not be able to provide access to all of the Information that we hold about you. We may not provide access to Information if doing so would likely reveal Information about a third party, could be expected to threaten the life or security of an individual, reveal confidential commercial information, if the Information is protected by a legally recognized privilege, if it was created as part of a settlement or dispute resolution process, or if it was collected in relation to the investigation of a breach of an agreement or a contravention of law. Talemetry will provide reasons to you if it refuses an access request.

### Safeguards

Where Talemetry considers it appropriate, having due regard to the sensitivity of the particular Information that we collect, use or disclose, and the laws we operate under, Talemetry uses encryption or authentication tools, among other methods, practices and procedures, to protect your Information irrespective of which format it is stored in. Our practices and procedures for safeguarding your Information are regularly reviewed. However, no method of Internet transmission or electronic storage is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security of your information.

E-mails you send to us are not necessarily secure when they are transmitted to us. If your communication is sensitive or includes confidential information, such as a credit card number, you may want to provide it by post or via the telephone instead.

It is important that you keep your User ID and password information (or other access information) related to your use of this Site (such as our career portal) secure and that you not share it with anyone, in order to safeguard your Information on our Site. There may be fraudulent “phishing” emails targeting individuals who the perpetrators believe might be registered users of this Site.  _We never send an unsolicited email after you register with us which requests users to visit a Web page or place a call and provide their user ID, password or any personal information._   _We will never ask you to confirm your user ID or password via email._   **If you ever receive such an email, do not log in from any referred link and do not provide any personal information.**  You should contact our Privacy Officer at +1-866-447-3933, +44-20-3287-2395, or +1-604-278-4414 immediately and inform us of the email.

Our employees receive privacy training. Employees are instructed to only use Information in adherence with the principles set forth in this Privacy Notice, our corporate privacy policy, and the laws applicable to our business. The only employees who have access to your Information are administrative and operational personnel who require such access to perform their work duties. Employees who misuse your Information are subject to disciplinary action.

### Changes to this Policy

Talemetry reserves the right to modify this Privacy Notice from time to time, so please review it regularly. If we make material changes to this Privacy Notice, we will notify you here and / or by notification in the Site. Please look at the top of this Privacy Notice to check the date that it was updated and to confirm that you are familiar with the terms of the most recent update. Your continued use of this Site will constitute your acceptance of the new terms and their application to your use of this Site and the Information disclosed for such use, including Information previously furnished us, as if they were the initial terms, and your consent to the use of your Information as described in this privacy notice and elsewhere at our Site.  _We will always seek your consent if we want to use your Information for purposes other than for those set out in this Privacy Notice or to which you have previously agreed._

### Contact Us

Talemetry will make information about its policies and practices relating to management of personal information readily available. Please direct any questions about our privacy policies and procedures, any requests for access to our records of your personal information and any other privacy related concerns or complaints to [privacy@talemetry.com](mailto:privacy@talemetry.com). All privacy related complaints will be acknowledged, recorded, investigated and responded to in accordance with applicable law.

You can contact us through our toll-free line at 1-866-447-3933, in the UK at +44-20-3287-2395 or otherwise at +1-604-278-4414; or by postal mail at:

Chief Privacy Officer  
Talemetry Inc.  
200 – 13799 Commerce Parkway,  
Richmond, BC, V6V 2N9 Canada

If you contact us by telephone, please note that telephone calls may be recorded for our mutual protection and security.

Talemetry has appointed Rolepoint Limited as its representative in the EU under Article 27 of the GDPR. If you are a resident of the European Union you may choose to postal mail our representative instead of our Canadian address at:

Rolepoint Limited  
Unit 4.07, 56 Shoreditch High Street  
London E1 6JJ  
Attn: Talemetry Privacy Representative

We welcome any suggestions or comments about this Privacy Notice.
